（縛虎申(ばくこしん)）やっと会えたな 宮元(きゅうげん)
So we finally meet, Gong Yuan!
（信(しん)）ンンッ…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
Timing
G_I_A
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Wang Qi Intrudes
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）大王さま
ただいま 報告が入りました
Your majesty,
I've just received a report.
（昌文君）
麃公(ひょうこう)将軍率いる我が秦国軍は―
Our Qin Army, led by General Biao Gong
has clashed directly with General Wu Qing, leading the Wei Army, at the Shegan Plain.
引き続き 蛇甘(だかん)平原にて
呉慶(ごけい)将軍率いる魏国(ぎこく)軍と交戦中
But against the fierce attack by the State of Wei's chariot corps, many of our soldiers have been lost
しかしながら―
魏国の戦車隊による猛攻で
多くの兵が失われたうえ
and the enemy has also created a formation atop a hill.
丘の上にも 敵方に布陣され
戦況は 極めて―
The state of the battle is extremely grim.
厳しいとのことです
（政(せい)）そうか
I see...
（貂(てん)）
“戦況は厳しい”って まさか…
The state of battle is grim...
Could it be...?
大丈夫だよな？ 信
You're okay, right, Xin?
でっかい手柄を上げて
帰ってくるよな？
Get some big achievements and come back, okay?
この戦で負けているようでは
中華統一への道など開けぬ
If we were to lose this battle,
no path towards uniting all of China will open.
頼むぞ！
I'm counting on you!
（宮元）なるほど
I see.
（宮元）奇跡の積み重ねで―
By a string of miracles, you managed to reach this place, have you...?
ここまで
たどりついたというわけか
ハァハァ…
（宮元）くだらんな
Meaningless.
奇跡とは非力な者に舞い降りる幸運
Miracles are good fortune that descend on the powerless.
そんなものに頼っているから
数万の兵が犬死にするのだ
Because you relied on such things, tens of thousands of soldiers will die meaningless deaths.
愚か者
（信）野郎！
Fools.
Bastard!
（縛虎申）犬死にではない
（信）ハッ…
They were not meaningless deaths.
死んでいった者 全ての
骸(むくろ)の橋を渡って―
I crossed the bridge of corpses
俺は ここまで来たのだ…
to reach this place!
フン…“仲間の犠牲”などと
美談を戦に持ち込む輩(やから)は―
Those who bring heart-warming tales of their comrades' sacrifices into battle
わしが 最も嫌悪する人種
are the type that disgust me more than any other.
Unit captain of the State of Qin, albeit a miracle, the fact that you are here is the truth.
秦国の部隊長よ　奇跡とはいえ
ここまで来たことは事実だ
だが 来ただけで何とする？
But what do you hope to accomplish from it?
わしを討ち 丘を奪い取らねば
何ら戦況は変わらん
Unless you defeat me and capture this hill, there will be no change in the state of this battle.
それができぬお前は
やはり ただの…
In the end, being unable to do that, yours will simply be...
a meaningless death!
犬死にだー！
Thousand Man General!
千人将ーっ！
わしを
ただの軍師だと思っていたのか？
Did you think I was merely a strategist?
かつては 呉慶さまと共に
前線を荒らした武人ぞ
Long ago, I fought alongside Lord Wu Qing, devastating the front lines as a warrior!
I'm astounded to hear you're a warrior!
“武人”が聞いてあきれる…
もはや 視力すら失った死人(しびと)の俺に
If you actually came with a sword to stab me,
わざわざ剣を うがちに来るとはな
even as corpse that loses his sight,
どうだ？ 宮元
今の俺の力も 単なる奇跡か？
what do you think now, Gong Yuan?
Is my power a mere miracle?
そう思っているなら
貴様らは絶対に麃公さまには勝てぬ
If that's what you believe, your lot will never defeat Lord Biao Gong!
Vice General of Wei, Wu Qing,
魏の副将 宮元…
討ち取ったぞ！
I've beaten you!
Lord Fu Hushen!
（部下）縛虎申さま！
（魏兵）宮元さま！
Lord Gong Yuan!
（尾平(びへい)）ウワッ…
What the hell is this brat?!
（魏兵）何なんだ？ このガキ
ウワッ！
（尾到(びとう)）すげえな 羌瘣(きょうかい)は…
（尾平）ああ ひょっとして―
Man, Qiang Lei's incredible.
Do you think that,
これなら 魏のヤツらを
全部 斬れるんじゃねえか？
he can cut down all of the Wei soldiers?
ウワッ…
（羌瘣）ハァ…
呼吸が尽きた
I'm out of breath.
戻るまで しんがりを頼む
（尾平たち）えっ！
I'm leaving the rear guard to you until I get back.
今だー！
Now!
（澤圭(たくけい)）ウワ～ッ！
So they've reached it?
そう来たか
（部下Ａ）縛虎申さま
Lord Fu Hushen.
魏国の兵の大半を斬り
生き残った者も逃走しました
We've killed the majority of Wei's soldiers
and the remainder all fled.
（部下Ｂ）我々の部隊が
宮元の陣営を討ち取ったのです
Our unit has taken Gong Yuan's camp.
（部下Ｃ）
しかし 丘の中腹で突破した
魏の守備隊が迫っております
Except for the Wei garrison we burst through to get to the heart of the hill.
（部下Ｂ）1,000を超す軍勢に対し
我らは10人と おりませぬ
Against a military force of over 1,000, we have less than 10 men.
（部下Ａ）
無念ですが せめて魏の旗を倒し
It's mortifying, but at least we were able to take down the Wei flag.
宮元の首を持って
一度 丘を下りましょう
Let's take Gong Yuan's head and retreat from the hill for now.
（信）バカ言ってんじゃねえよ！
Don't be idiots!
下りたいヤツは下りやがれ
俺は ここで戦うぞ
Whoever wants to go down, go!
I'm gonna stay here and fight.
（部下Ａ）なんだと 貴様！
What'd you say, bastard?!
歩兵のぶんざいで 口を慎め！
（信）千人将は―
Watch your mouth, infantryman!
Thousand Man General said it's because our allies made sacrifices
味方全員の犠牲があったから
ここまで来られたと言った
that we were able to make it here.
…てことは この丘を取るために
みんな 死んだんだ
Which means everyone died so we could capture this hill!
We can't let go of this hill
その丘を 1,000人や そこらが
追ってきたぐらいで―
just because a thousand or so guys are coming to take it back!
簡単に手放すかってんだ！
バカか 貴様は！
（部下Ａ）1,000人だぞ！
Are you an idiot, bastard?!
There's a thousand of them!
小僧… 名は？
Kid... What's your name?
It's Xin.
信だ
信…
Xin...
Listen here, Xin.
いいか？ 信… 勇猛と無謀は違う
そこをはき違えると―
Bravery and recklessness are different.
If you mix those up, you'll just all die without leaving anyone left.
何も残さず 早く死ぬ
皆と共に 丘を下れ…
Descend the hill with the others...
That's an order...!
命令だ！
フッ… 愚か者が…
You fool...
生きて
丘を下りられると思っておるのか？
Do you think you'd be able to descend this hill alive?
見苦しいぞ 宮元！
What an unsightly lie, Gong Yuan!
You know there are no garrison units on the opposite side of the hill!
丘の反対側に
守備隊がいないことは分かっている
貴様の首を持って
ゆっくり下りてやる
We're going to take your head and have an easy time going down the hill!
お前たちは 何も分かっておらぬ…
You fools know nothing...
丸城(がんじょう)と同じく 秦国の者どもは―
It will be just like what happened at Wan Castle...
All of the people of Qin... will be slaughtered...
皆殺し…
（部下Ｂ）どうした？ 小僧
What is it, kid?!
（部下Ｂ）バカな…
Impossible!
（部下Ａ）
こんな大軍 一体 どこから…
Where on earth did this huge group come from?!
あっ… あの奥の丘！
That inner mountain!
There are no soldiers on that hill the main Wei Army was supposed occupy!
魏の本隊が
陣取っていたはずの丘に兵がいない
This means... they've been moved by someone else!
…ということは自ら動きだしたんだ
魏国軍の総大将 呉慶が
（信）ハッ…
The State of Wei Army Commander General, Wu Qing!
Where all those big flags are gathered...
あのでっけえ旗が集まってるとこ…
That's the Wei General?!
あれが 魏の大将？
Yeah, that's right, kid.
ああ そうだ 小僧
That's the Great General of Wei, Wu Qing!
あれが 魏国の大将軍
呉慶だ！
Wei's... Great General!
魏国の大将軍…
戦いてえ！
I wanna fight him!
（尚鹿(しょうかく)）
何を考えてるんだ？ 麃公将軍は
What's General Biao Gong thinking?!
（尚鹿）
このままでは長くは もたんぞ
As things are going, this won't last long!
Lord Shang Lu!
（部下Ｄ）尚鹿さま！
丘の上の魏の旗が落ちましたぞ！
（尚鹿）なに？
The Wei flags on top of the hill have been fallen!
What?!
フッ… やりやがったな 縛虎申
You did it, Fu Hushen, you damn bastard.
（部下Ｄ）
尚鹿さま 赤伝者が来ます！
Lord Shang Lu!
A red messenger has arrived!
（尚鹿）将軍からの緊急指令か
An emergency order from the general?!
What this time?!
今度は何だ？
A report to the 1st, 2nd, and 4th armies!
（赤伝者）
第１ ２ ４軍 全軍に告ぐ！
An urgent report!
至急 丘に登り 我らが陣とすべし！
繰り返す
We're ascending the mountain and forming an encampment!
I repeat!
全軍 丘に登り 布陣すべし！
（壁(へき)）ハッ…
All armies, ascend the mountain and create a battle formation!
これだけ押されてるのに
ムチャクチャだ！
We're being pushed this much already! That's insane!
この戦況じゃ
丘の麓にも近づけねえぞ！
In the state of this battle, we can't even get close to the foot of the mountain!
Right, Bi?!
なあ？ 壁
どうした？ 壁
あさってのほう向いて
What's wrong, Bi?
You're facing the opposite direction.
（壁）どういうことだ？
What is this?
なぜ
こんな所にいるのだ？
Why is he here?!
State of Qin General  Wang Qi
王騎(おうき)将軍！
General Wang Qi!
おい 壁　しかたないから
俺たちも丘を取りに行くぞ
Hey, Bi!
We've got no choice, so we're heading for the hill, too!
（壁）待て 尚鹿
（尚鹿）えっ？
Wait, Shang Lu!
あの王騎将軍が現れた
That General Wang Qi has appeared...
何かが起こる…
Something big... is going to happen!
You've got the same imprecise fighting style as always, Biao Gong.
（王騎）相変わらず 大ざっぱな
戦いぶりですねえ 麃公さんは
*Wang Qi's
Aide
Teng
Yes, sir! But...
（騰(とう)）はっ… ですが
that is what's terrifying about Biao Gong.
それが 麃公将軍の
恐ろしい所です
As for Wu Qing...
（王騎）となると 呉慶さんは…
That hill over there looks like it'll have a good view.
あちらの丘のほうが
見晴らしがよさそうですねえ
そう思いませんか？ 騰
Don't you think, Teng?
はっ！ 間違いありません
Yes, sir! Undoubtedly!
But Lord, it is a crime to joining a battle without expressed permission.
しかし 殿 許可なく
戦に加わるのは 罪になります
Unfortunately, this is the furthest we are able to set foot.
残念ですが 我々が 足を
踏み入れられるのは ここまでです
誰も戦に加わるとは言ってませんよ
Who said anything about joining a battle?
私は ただ
あの丘に登りたいと思っただけです
I simply want to climb that hill.
途中
ジャマな者は排除いたしますが
Though I'll be removing anyone who obstructs me on the way.
Brilliant, Lord.
さすが殿　完璧(かんぺき)な言い訳です
A perfect excuse.
では…
Now, then.
（尚鹿）
あの急な崖を駆け下りてくるぞ
どこの騎馬隊だ？
They're running down the side of that steep cliff?!
What mounted unit is that?!
王騎将軍と その配下の兵たちだ
（尚鹿）王騎将軍だと？ バカな
It's General Wang Qi and his subordinate soldiers.
General Wang Qi?! That's insane!
将軍は
もう何年も前に引退したはずだ
He was supposed to have retired as a general many years ago!
王騎将軍…
General Wang Qi!
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
（尚鹿）
そうか 再び戦場に舞い戻られたか
I see...
So he's returned to the battlefield once again,
秦国の怪鳥が！
the Mystery Bird of Qin!
壁隊！
突入した援軍に 全力で続け！
Bi Unit! Follow the reinforcements that just broke through with all your strength!
Shang Lu, the same! Let's go!
尚鹿隊も同様だ　行くぞ！
縛虎申さま 呉慶の本軍の
反対側から 丘を下ります
Lord Fu Hushen, Wu Qing's main army has descended the hill on the opposite side.
（部下Ｃ）途中 魏の守備隊と
斬り合いになりますが ご辛抱を
We'll clash with Wei's garrison unit, but please try to endure it.
（縛虎申）
バカな… 俺を置いていけ
You idiots, leave me.
（部下Ｂ）
敵が来る所へ置いてなどいけません
We can't leave you in a place where the enemy is coming!
それに 逝(い)かれるならば我らの肩で
（縛虎申）アア…
If you're going to die... do it on our shoulders.
俺も肩を…
（部下Ａ）お前は こっちだ
I'll give you a shoulder...
You're needed here.
This is... the enemy Vice General's head?
これは 敵の副将の首
（部下Ａ）そう
Yes.
That's the military gain the Fu Hushen Unit made!
我ら縛虎申隊が勝ち取った戦果だ
何が何でも 秦国軍陣営に持ち帰れ
No matter what happens, bring it back to the Qin Army camp!
失敗は許さんぞ
（信）俺でいいのか？
Failure will not be tolerated!
Are you okay with me doing it?
It is Lord Fu Hushen's order.
縛虎申さまの命令であり
我らにも異存はない
We have no objections either.
引き受けた
Got it.
よし みんなでサクッと下りようぜ
下りは 上りより楽ちんだ
All right, let's all make a quick descent!
Going down'll be way easier than going up.
えっ？
（王騎）もう お帰りですか？
Going already?
Things were finally getting interesting.
せっかく
面白くなってきたんですけどねえ
My legs... can't take it anymore!
（尾到）脚が… もうムリ！
（澤圭）
このままでは追いつかれます！
At this rate, they'll catch us!
もうダメだ… アアッ…
We're screwed!
（尾到）き… 騎馬隊
（尾平）助かった…
A-A mounted unit?
We're saved!
皆さん あれを見てください！
Everyone!
Look, there!
（尾到）やった… ついに やった…
We did it... We finally did it...
（尾平）俺たちが―
We...
( Flags - Qin )
took those Wei guys' hill!
魏のヤツらの丘を取ったんだ！
（部下Ａ）宮元が陣取っていた丘に
我らの旗が立ちましたぞ
Our flags are standing on the hill Gong Yuan was encamped on.
Your valor has opened a path for us!
あなたの武勇が
道を切り開いたのです…
バカが…
I don't believe it...
（壁）まだ お前から
学ぶことがあったような気がする
I feel like I still had things to learn from you.
It's unfortunate, Fu Hushen.
残念だ 縛虎申…
（信）な… 何だ？ こいつは
Wh-Who is this guy...?!
From the reaction around here, he doesn't seem like an enemy...
周りの反応からして
敵じゃなさそうだが
But he doesn't feel like an ally, either...!
味方って感じもしねえ
分からねえ…
I can't tell...
強さも 怖さも こいつ…
I'm feeling both strength... and fear... from this guy...
He's too gigantic! I can't tell!
でかすぎて 分からねえ！
ンンッ…
（王騎）おや？
Oh?
昌文君が言っていた童とは
あなたのことですか？
Are you the youngster Changwenjun mentioned?
名前は 確か…
I do believe your name is...
Xin.
“信”
（信）ハッ…
あんた
昌文君のおっさんの仲間か？
You're old man Changwenjun's comrade?
I'm not so much a comrade...
仲間というか ンフフフッ…
（信）うん？
as a lover!
愛人です
ココココッ…
冗談ですよ　王騎冗談
That was a joke. A Wang Qi joke.
そうですか　どうりで…
あなた 遠目にも目立ってましたよ
Is that right?
By the way, I saw you from far away.
えっ？
（王騎）しかし―
But it was a different story from the youngster Changwenjun implied to me.
昌文君が推していた童と聞いては
話が別ですねえ
はっきり言って
期待外れもいいところです
If I'm being honest, I'm disappointed.
What, old man?
なんだと？ おっさん
俺が弱(よえ)えって言ってんのか？
Are you sayin' I'm weak?
そのとおり
Exactly.
んじゃ 試してみっかよ？ 唇巨人！
Then why don't you try me?!
You big-lipped giant!
ンフフフッ…“唇巨人”ねえ
うまいこと おっしゃる
Big-lipped giant, eh?
What a comeback.
But among those who have pointed a sword at me,
ですが 私に剣を向けた者は―
１人残らず
この宝刀で両断されますよ
every last one of them was split in half with this treasured sword.
Are you prepared for that?
その覚悟はありますか？
そんな大物(おおもん)が当たっかよ
俺は メチャクチャ速(はえ)えぞ！
Like something that big could hit!
I'm fast as all hell!
ンフフッ… その辺ですよ
勢いが先行してるといいますか
Now, now.
Do you think you have the lead in momentum?
分かってますか？
Didn't you know?
あなた さっきから ずっと
死地に立ってるんですよ
You've been standing at the precipice of death for quite a while now.
て… てめえ！
Y-You bastard!
血迷うな 信！
Don't lose control of yourself, Xin!
壁！
Bi!
今は 力を尽くして
魏国の兵と戦うときだ
Now's the time to be exhausting every ounce of our strength to fight the State of Wei!
相手も わきまえず
剣を振り回している場合ではない！
This isn't the time to be swinging your swords around without discerning who is really your foe!
You're okay, Xin!
（尾平）無事だったか 信！
（澤圭）良かった…
（尾平）生きてただけで上出来だぜ
ク～ッ…
It's incredible that you're even still alive!
そっちこそ 全員 無事だったか
You, too.
I'm so glad you guys are all okay.
うん？ 羌瘣は？
Where's Qiang Lei?
Well, young Qiang Lei is...
それが 羌瘣君は…
ここにいる
Over here.
Qiang Lei...
（尾到）羌瘣 お前 いつの間に…
When did you get there?
（尾平）
…ていうか どこ行ってたんだ？
And hey, where did you go in the first place?
王騎将軍 援軍 痛み入ります
General Wang Qi!
We are indebted to you for your reinforcements.
この戦況の中 将軍が
到着されたことは 正に天の助け
That you arrived here in this state of war was truly an act of heaven.
そして今
この丘にある軍の指揮権は―
And now, I offer the right to command on this hill to you, to act as general.
将軍たる貴殿のもとに
あろうと存じます
Then, us included, the whole army will be led under your eyes to attack the Wei Army!
なれば 直ちに我らを含め
全軍を率いて 眼下の魏軍に突撃を
丘の上という地の利もあるうえに
With the added advantage of the high ground on this hill
with an army led by you, General Wang Qi, we will surely be victorious!
王騎将軍が率いる軍ならば
絶対に勝てます
ンフフフッ…
相変わらず生真面目ですね 壁副官
You're far too serious as usual, Aide Bi.
But unfortunately, we did not come here to be your reinforcements.
しかし 残念ながら 我々は
援軍に来たわけではありませんよ
うん？
（王騎）ただ―
We only wished to come to this hill.
この丘に来たかっただけです
ねえ？ 騰
Isn't that right, Teng?
はっ！ 最高の眺めです
Yes, sir!
It is a spectacular view.
And Aide Bi, you said you're sure to be victorious,
（王騎）それに 壁副官
あなた “絶対に勝てる”と
おっしゃいましたが
but that shows too much contempt to General Wu Qing.
それは
少々 呉慶将軍を侮り過ぎですよ
9-layer spear wall!
（大軍の移動する音）
（王騎）ほ～ら ねっ？
Oh, what's this?
Look at his appearance over there.
こちらの様子を見て
すかさず陣形を変えてきましたよ
Without a moment's delay, he changed his formation.
戦況の変化を繊細に察し
用心深く―
He's made a delicate judgement of the changes in the state of the battle
and taken a cautious and bold action.
かつ 大胆に動く軍略の才能は
魏国随一
In terms of talent for strategy, the State of Wei is superior.
更に 丸城で見せたように
先陣を行く武勇も 兼ね備えている
And as shown at Wan Castle,
he possesses the bravery to travel with the vanguard.
魏の将軍 呉慶は 間違いなく
列国の脅威となる名将です
The General of Wei, Wu Qing, is undoubtedly
an excellent general that will become a threat to many countries.
そんな… 数も多くて
大将も すごいんじゃ 俺たち…
No way...
Not only do they have better numbers, they have a great general. And we...
ンフッ… 数は関係ありませんよ
Numbers don't matter.
From its start, this was not that sort of battle, you see.
この戦いは 最初から
そういう戦いではありませんからね
武将には２つの型があると思います
I believe there are two types of military generals.
The first is the resourceful type, like Wu Qing.
１つは 呉慶さんのような知略型
And the other is the instinctual type that fights with wild intuition.
もう１つは 野生の直感で
戦うような本能型です
Youngster Xin, would you like to make a bet with me?
童 信…
私と ひとつ賭けをしませんか？
（信）えっ？
（王騎）知略が勝つのか
Will resourceful win?
本能が勝つのか
Or will instinct win?
（信）本能？
（王騎）無論…
Instinct?
Of course, I mean the commander of the State of Qin Army, Biao Gong.
秦国軍の
総大将 麃公さんのことです
俺たちの大将と 魏の大将と―
You wanna bet whether or not our general or the Wei general will win?
どっちが勝つのか
賭けるってことか？
そのとおり
Exactly.
Please, enough jokes, General Wang Qi!
（壁）ざれ言は
やめていただきたい 王騎将軍！
（王騎）ざれ言とは心外ですねえ
I wouldn't dream of joking about this.
“知略”対“本能”
Resourcefulness vs instinct.
Among generals, this is an eternal theme.
これは
武将にとって 永遠の題目ですよ
武将の題目？
Eternal Theme?!
（壁）しかし 今は―
But now is the time to be thinking about how to attack the enemy before our eyes with our own hands!
いかにして 我々の手で
眼下の敵を討つかを考えるとき
この場におられぬ麃公将軍を
論じている場合ではありますまい！
This is surely not the time to be discussing about Biao Gong, who is not even here!
ンフフフッ… そうでしょうか？
Isn't he?
Bi!
（尚鹿）壁！
（壁）うん？
Our Qin Army's mounted unit are making dash around this hill!
我が秦国軍の騎馬隊が
この丘を回り込んで 疾走している
And they're being led by General Biao Gong!
（尚鹿）率いているのは麃公将軍だ
（壁）なに？
What?!
Where?!
どこだ？
ひと目で分かる
I can tell with one look.
あれが 麃公将軍…
大将自ら 先頭に立ち―
That's General Biao Gong!
The general is leading the unit himself,
あの魏の大軍に 突っ込む気だ
and he's going to rush right into that huge Wei Army!
As always, unless he's in the center of a huge fire
相変わらず
最後は大火の中心にいなければ―
気が済まないようですねえ
麃公さんは
that Biao Gong is never satisfied.
In the course of this long war, the scope of the armies have grown.
長き戦乱で 軍の規模は増大し
今では 数十万の戦い
It is now a war of hundreds of thousands.
But the larger an army gets,
しかし 軍が大きくなればなるほど
それを率いる将軍の才能と―
the more the war is influenced by the talent of the general leading it.
力が戦を左右する
（信）ンッ…
結局 戦は武将のものです
Ultimately, war is its generals.
Biao Gong, eh?
麃公か…
この呉慶の軍に 奇襲は通用せぬ
A surprise attack will never work against my army.
（王騎）
また 呉慶さんが陣形を変えました
Wu Qing has changed his battle formation again.
He's assumed a stance to catch Biao Gong's assault.
麃公さんの突撃を
受け止める構えです
呉慶さんは 戦を
理詰めの盤面と捉えていますねえ
Wu Qing is treating the war as a game board of logic.
一方 麃公さんの戦は
燃え盛る ひとつの大きな炎
On the other hand, Biao Gong's war is one big blazing flame.
その火力が極大に達した今を
麃公さんが見逃すはずがありません
And now that that flame is burning at its maximum,
Biao Gong will be sure not to let it slip away.
理解できませんか？ ンフフフッ…
Don't understand?
呉慶さんも
麃公さんの戦を理解できません
Wu Qing cannot understand Biao Gong's way of war either.
しかし 麃公さんも―
But neither can Biao Gong
see all of Wu Qing's strategy.
呉慶さんの軍略を
見切っているわけではありません
どちらが是か
Which is right?
どちらが非か
Which is wrong?
これは どちらか一方の首が
飛ばねば 分かりかねますねえ
We won't know unless one of their heads goes flying.
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
（信）俺は
さっきから将軍と話をしてたのか…
Have I been talking with a general this whole time?
Xin saw his future there.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）信は そこに未来を見た
そして 目指すものの重みを知る
And learned the burden of the thing he seeks.
The Meaning of General
End
次回 “将軍の意味”
Next time,